An Inventory to the Pardee Lowe papers, 1911-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- UC Berkeley Institute of Slavic Studies PhD files, 1950s-1960s. (Box 333)
  Includes PhD studies selection, grade reports, and correspondence regarding projected completion date, and letter regarding the recruitment potential of selected classmates for service with USIA or CIA
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1969-1971. (Box 333)
  Includes documents related to Lowe's 1969 survey trip related to his work with UNESCO, with some documents related to travel in 1971
- China subject file, undated, probably 1960s (Box 334)
- Documents related to giving banquets in San Francisco, 1934 and 1937 (Box 334)
- Psychological warfare subject file, undated, probably 1950s (Box 334)
- "Communist Penetration of the IPR," typescript with holographic edits. (Box 334)
  Includes timeline of the IPR, 1925-1949
- K. C. Li newsletters, 1941-1942. (Box 334)
  Consists of typescript copies of newsletters by Li in the form of letters from Li in the U.S. to Madame Chiang Kai-shek. See also box 486
- Father and Glorious Descendant files, 1941-1946. (Box 334)
  Includes motion picture companies and magazine correspondence and publicity notes, 1942-1944
- Correspondence, Frau Rat. M. Rode, Wittenberg, Germany, 1931-1937. (Box 334)
  Includes appointment book pages, 24 June-1 September, 1931
- American Bureau for Medical Aid to China documents, bulletins and clippings, 1940-1941 (Box 334)
- Institute of Pacific Relations Yosemite Conference planning documents, 1936 (Box 334)
- Stanford University class notes, 1927-1930 (Box 334)
- Sociology subject file, 1920s-1964. (Box 334)
  Includes Lowe's Stanford Economics 2 "Elements of Sociology" class notes, and clippings, 1930s-1964
- Correspondence, 1942-1945 (bulk 1944-1945). (Box 335)
  Mainly relates to Lowe's assignment at the U.S. Army Counter Intelligence Corps in China
- Stanford Alumni in China documents, 1947-1948. (Box 335)
  Mainly newsletters and correspondence regarding Alumni events
- LaPiere work files, 1940-1941, undated. (Box 335)
  Mainly correspondence, edits to manuscript, and documents related to publicity work for LaPiere's When the Living Strive, 1940-1941 and undated
- "China's Marco Polo," draft, typescript with edits, probably 1940 (Box 335)
- Father and Glorious Descendant correspondence, 1941-1944. (Box 335)
  Related to securing permissions to include in the novel material previously published and to publicity work
- USIS work clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 335)
- University of California, Berkeley, "Slavic Syllabus," 1952 March (Box 335)
- Subject files, UNESCO work, 1973-1974 (Box 336)
  - Clippings, with some printed material (Box 336)
  - Population subject file. (Box 336)
    Includes Population Literature 1935 October 20, a bibliographic quarterly by the Population Association of America
- Chinese American and Chinatown organizations subject file, 1974-1975. (Box 337)
  Consists mainly of clippings, with some correspondence, printed material including Chinese-language flyers for movies in San Francisco Chinatown
- Asian Studies Annual Meeting, Boston, Massachusetts, agenda, notes, and writings by others, 1974 April 2 (Box 337)
- Subject files, UNESCO work, 1973-1974. (Box 337)
  Consists mainly of clippings and printed material as well as a portion of an 8-year development plan for educational work in Kenya
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1966-1973 (Box 338)
  - Correspondence, reports, and holographic notes related to UNESCO work, especially vocational education in the U.S., 1966-1973 (Box 338)
  - Bureau of International Organizations Affairs, 1971 January (Box 338)
  - UNESCO work printed materials (Box 338)
- Subject file materials, mainly clippings, 1970s (Box 338)
- Subject files on health topics, 1950s-1970s. (Box 339)
  Includes clippings and documents related to Lowe's medical records
- "The Agency in Brief," USIA administrative document, 1962 January. (Box 340)
  Relates to the history, operations, personnel, and legislative authority for USIA
- Subject files, 1988-1991. (Box 340)
  Mainly consists of clippings
  - USSR (Box 340)
  - U.S.A. (Box 340)
  - USAID (Box 340)
  - Taiwan (Box 340)
  - United Nations (Box 340)
  - UNESCO (Box 340)
  - Nisei (Box 340)
  - Religion (Box 340)
  - Singapore (Box 340)
  - South Africa (Box 340)
- Vocational and technical education files, 1960s-1970s. (Box 341)
  Includes some correspondence, processed reports, and printed material
- USSR subject files, 1989-1991. (Box 341)
  Consists of clippings and printed material
- Rotary Club of Taipei files, 1959-1960s (Box 342)
- Public Health subject file, 1960s-1985. (Box 342)
  Consists mainly of clippings and printed material
- United Nations memos, 1960s (Box 342)
- Clippings, 1985 (Box 342)
- Taiwan Subject files, 1959-1970. (Box 343)
  Consists mainly of clippings, printed ephemera, and notes, particularly related to visiting churches in Taiwan
  - Motion pictures, consists of large format flyers relating to Taiwanese movies being shown at theaters in San Francisco, New York, and Boston (Box 343)
  - Music. (Box 343)
    Contains printed material and clippings related to the Chinese National Foo-Hsing Opera Academy, Republic of China
  - Military (Box 343)
  - Language (Box 343)
  - Leaders (Box 343)
  - Refugees (Box 343)
  - Religion (Box 343)
  - Churches (Box 343)
  - Resources (Box 343)
  - Return to Mainland (Box 343)
- "Military Assistance Advisory Group Republic of China, APO 63, San Francisco, California," printed directory of MAAG staff in form of organizational chart, 1963 April 1 (Box 343)
- State Department and Free China files, 1950s-1970s (bulk 1950s-1960s) (Box 344)
- Free Asia Committee subject file, 1951-1953 and undated (Box 344)
  Consisting of memoranda, prospectus, press release, and clippings
- Chinese opera subject file. (Box 344)
  Consists mainly of printed ephemera related to U.S. performances of Foo Hsing Theater performances in the U.S., 1961-1962, and for Fulbright scholars in Taipei, Taiwan, 1961 June 10
- U.S. Officers' Open Mess, Taipei, Taiwan, 1963-1964 (Box 344)
- U.S. Embassy in Tokyo, Japan, 1964 (Box 344)
- Taiwan subject files, 1950s-1972. (Box 344)
  Includes notes, typescript writing drafts, copies of outgoing letters, reports and memos, by USIA, USIS, and others, printed material, and clippings
  - Population (Box 344)
  - Propaganda (Box 344)
  - Philosophy (Box 344)
  - Police (Box 344)
  - Pollution (Box 344)
  - Labor (Box 344)
  - Overseas Chinese (Taiwan) (Box 344)
  - Offshore Islands, including the multinationally-contested islands Matsu, Quemoy, and Senkakus (also known as Tiao Yu Tai or Diao Yu Tai) (Box 344)
  - Action Committee for Tiao Yu Tai, Washington, DC, mailings (Box 344)
  - "Non-USIA Informational Facilities Available in Taiwan," typescript, 1958 July 7 (Box 344)
  - National Geographic Society correspondence, 1956 December 11, in response to a request for Lowe to review the manuscript on Taiwan for a forthcoming issue of National Geographic magazine (Box 344)
- Subject files, 1940-1973 (bulk 1950s-1960s) (Box 345-346.)
- Publications, Taiwan (Box 345)
- China publicity and propaganda file, 1940-1973. (Box 345)
  Includes some typescript correspondence with the San Francisco Committee to Aid China, 1940, and USIS and USIA typescript reports
- Korea file, 1950s-1972 (Box 345)
  which includes United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) memos, 1960s
- U.S. Army (Rear) Office of Psychological Warfare Officer, reports, 1957 (Box 346)
- Japan subject files, 1940-1975 (Box 347-348.)
  - NHK TV, Japan's educational television station, printed material (Box 347-348.)
- Korea subject file, 1953-1970 (bulk 1953-1954) (Box 347-348.)
- Clippings (Box 347)
- Course notes and other materials related to Lowe's Stanford University undergraduate studies, with some additional clippings, 1927-1932 (Box 348)
- Rotary Club in the U.S. and Taipei correspondence and other printed material related to membership, 1949-1960 (Box 348)
- Taiwan subject files, 1959-1980s. (Box 349)
  Includes holographic notes, correspondence, and other documents
  - USIS work materials (Box 349)
  - Military Assistance and Advisory Group, Taiwan (MAAG-Taiwan) and the Asia Foundation memos and clippings (Box 349)
- Stanford undergraduate coursework files, 1929-1930 (Box 349)
- Taiwan subject files, 1958-1970. (Box 350-351.)
  Includes correspondence, holographic notes
  - U.S. Embassy and USIS directories and phone lists, 1964-1965 (Box 350)
  - UNESCO and USAID work files related to mainland China (Box 350)
  - Rotary Club of Taipei, Taiwan, participation, 1961-1965 (Box 351)
- Vietnam subject file, 1969-1971 (Box 351)
- Social Science Research Conference of the Pacific Coast files, 1933, undated. (Box 352-353.)
  See also box 360
- Vietnam subject files (Box 352)
- Veteran status and educational assistance under the State of California Department of Veterans Affairs Division of Educational Assistance, 1949-1954 (Box 353)
- Subject files (Box 353)
  - Population, including population and education, 1960s-1970s (Box 353)
  - Religion, 1920s-1970s (Box 353)
  - Religion, 1940-1970s (bulk 1950s-1970s) (Box 354)
  - Vietnam, 1973-1974 (Box 354)
- State Department bulletins and clippings, 1970s (Box 354)
- Clippings on investing, 1960s-1970s (Box 354)
- PhD research files and correspondence, 1953-1957, undated (Box 355)
- UNESCO work documents related to the Philippines and Singapore, 1960s-1970s (Box 355)
- Philippines subject files, 1930s-1970s (Box 355)
- Clippings files on the U.S., 1978-1980 (Box 355)
- Clippings files Sikkim, 1962 (Box 355)
- USSR subject files, 1930s-1980s, undated. (Box 356-357.)
  - Correspondence including related to Lowe's review for the Research Program on the USSR of Professor Butov's manuscript on the Chinese Eastern Railroad (Box 356-357.)
  - Draft writings and typescript notes (Box 356-357.)
  - PhD student papers by Lowe (Box 356-357.)
  - USIS and UNESCO work documents (Box 356-357.)
  - Clippings (Box 356-357.)
- Subject files related to tracking investments, 1950s-1980s (Box 356-357.)
- USSR subject files, 1950s-1972 (Box 358)
- Clippings related to President Lyndon Baines Johnson, 1971-1972 (Box 358)
- Subject files on creative and biographical writing, containing mostly clippings (Box 358)
- Subject files on authors Pearl S. Buck and Lin Yu-tang, 1940s-1970s (Box 358)
- Clippings related to U.S. military conscription, 1940 (Box 358)
- Biographical and other related documents in support of an application for military dependent benefits (Box 358)
- San Francisco newspapers issues, 1937 and 1940 (Box 358)
  Related to San Francisco annual budget, housing and relief needs survey, and San Francisco's Diamond Jubilee
- Creative, biographical, and sociological writing subject files, 1928-1950s. (Box 359-360.)
  Includes typescript draft writings, some with holographic edits, 1928-1930s and undated
- Notes and outlines for a writing project based on Lowe's family genealogy and history, undated, likely 1950s (Box 359-360.)
- Family genealogy documents, in Chinese, undated (Box 359-360.)
- Clippings related to "interracial" marriages, including marriage between Jews and gentiles, 1930s (Box 359-360.)
- Institute of Pacific Relations study files (Box 359-360.)
  - "Chinatown Changes: A Descriptive Study of the Changing Living Conditions of San Francisco's Chinese Community," 1937 April 30, partial typescript draft of monograph sponsored by the Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 359)
  - Correspondence and reports, 1936 (Box 359)
  - Project methodology (Box 359)
  - "Categorical Outline of a Sociological Study of San Francisco's Chinatown," typescript, 1936 (Box 359)
  - Proposed critique of study scope and methodology by B. L., IPR, 1936 April 30 (Box 360)
- "A Report of the Chinese Department of the State Emergency Relief Administration of San Francisco," typescript, 1934 September (Box 360)
- 1943 book files (Box 360)
  - Congratulatory letters, 1943 (Box 360)
  - Reprinting correspondence with Little, Brown, and Company, and Stanford University Press, 1951-1952 (Box 360)
- Subject files consisting mainly of clippings and some correspondence (Box 360)
  - Sino-Japanese War (Box 360)
  - U.S. boycott of Japan, American Committee for Non-participation in Japanese Aggression (Box 360)
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1939-1941 (Box 360)
    and clippings on U.S. Army, 1940s. See also box 359
  - Churches and other religious organizations include typescript, holographic, and ephemeral printed documents (Box 360)
- Writings related to religious organizations (Box 360)
- Writings on the YMCA, especially the YMCA of Oakland, California, and its Young Men's Division (YMD), 1920s-1930s and undated (Box 360)
- International House (of Berkeley, CA, New York, NY, and Chicago, IL) file, 1930s (Box 360)
- International House Alumni group activities in Shanghai, China, 1947-1948 (Box 360)
- Social Science Research Conference of the Pacific Coast correspondence, notes, and reports, 1930-1934 (Box 360)
- Dr. Hu Shih's speaking at the Commonwealth Club of San Francisco, 1937 September 29 (Box 360)
- "Hu Shih - China's Philosopher-Statesman," biography by Lowe, undated (Box 360)
- Harvard MBA files, 1931, undated. (Box 360)
  Includes correspondence and other documents related to Lowe's study of the Hamburg-American [Steamship] Line as part of a Harvard MBA project on U.S. corporations engaged in business in Germany under German laws
- Subject files on African Americans, 1920s-1970s (Box 361-364.)
  Includes clippings, some reports, and other printed material related to the conditions of African Americans
  - Sociological studies and data (Box 361-364.)
  - Desegregation and integration (Box 361-364.)
  - Development of Black studies and African American studies (Box 361-364.)
  - Race riots in the U.S. (Box 361-364.)
- World Court and the League of Nations subject files, 1920s-1970s (Box 361-364.)
- League of Nations Pavilion at the New York World's Fair printed material, 1939 (Box 361-364.)
- Guggenheim Foundation application files, 1941-1942 (Box 361-364.)
- University of California Alumni Club of Shanghai participation, 1947 (Box 361)
- Draft writings, notes, correspondence, class notes, and clippings related to religion and science, 1911-1930s (Box 361)
- International House of the University of California, Berkeley planning correspondence, 1930s (Box 361)
- Ford Foundation Board on Overseas Training and Research application files for PhD research, 1954 (Box 363)
  Includes typescript biographical material, correspondence, and plan of research
- Clippings and printed material related to foundations, 1940s-1970s. (Box 363)
  Includes the Asia Foundation
- USEFC memos regarding U.S. government policy and administration of the U.S. Educational Foundation in China and Fullbright program, 1948 and undated (Box 364)
- World Bank subject files, especially relating to Africa, 1960s-1973 (Box 364)
- Subject files, 1973-1975 (Box 365)
- Subject file consisting of clippings related to Ravenswood High, East Palo Alto, California, 1973-1975 (Box 365)
  Particularly concerning issues related to desegregation and response to plans to close the school
- Patricia Lowe schoolwork, 1974-1975 (Box 365)
- Draft writings and notes related to the history of the IPR, Owen Lattimore, and Frederick V. Field, including bibliographic notes, undated, typescript and holographic (Box 366)
- Subject file material, 1973 and 1977 (bulk 1977) (Box 366)
- Ephemera related to San Francisco Chinatown (Box 366)
- U.S. Education Foundation in China files, with additional materials related to the U.S. Department of State Educational Exchange Activities, 1948-1960s (Box 367)
- Subject file material related to Taiwan and to Japan, 1960s-1970s (Box 367)
- Department of State documents related to India, 1960s (Box 367)
- Clippings, 1977 (Box 368)
- Clippings, 1970s-1981 (Box 369)
- Institute of Pacific Relations files, 1933, undated (Box 370)
  - "General Instructions for the Cooperators of K. A. Wittfogel in the Field of Chinese Economic and Social History," Karl A. Wittfogel typescript, undated (Box 370)
- Subject files on sex, 1930s-1960s. (Box 370)
  Includes sex hygiene literature, including booklets by the War Work Council of the YMCA, 1918-1919, sexual morality educational fiction, 1930, and clippings
- Chinatown subject files, 1930s-1970s (Box 370)
- Writing by Lowe, 1979 September 2, typescript, contrasting the ceremony and reception for an interracial marriage that day with his own in 1931 (Box 370)
- "Chinatown and the California Cable Car Company," Edgar Kahn typescript, undated, and working files and correspondence, 1937 (Box 370)
- Subject files. (Box 370)
  Includes draft writings, notes, correspondence, and clippings
  - Chinatown of World War I (Box 370)
  - World War II (Box 370)
  - Korean War (Box 370)
  - Sino-Japanese war clippings, 1930s (Box 370)
- San Francisco and Oakland Chinese Telephone Directory, Pacific Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1938 March (Box 370)
- San Francisco Chinese Directory including Oakland-East Bay Section, Jimmy Lum Advertising Service, San Francisco, Ming Sing Printing Company, 1949 (Box 370)
- Golden Star Company catalog of new records, San Francisco, Ming Sing Printing Company, undated, in Chinese (Box 370)
- Subject files on religion, 1919-1970s. (Box 371)
  Includes draft writings, clippings, and printed material in English and Chinese
  - Religion in Chinatown, San Francisco, Oakland, and other Chinatowns (Box 371)
  - Religion among Chinese Americans (Box 371)
  - Religion in China (Box 371)
  - Christian and evangelical missionary work, 1930s-1970s (Box 371)
  - Missionary periodicals (Box 371)
  - The Christian Chinese Student issues, 1920s-1932 (Box 371)
- Subject file on sex, 1919-1971. (Box 371)
  Includes holographic notes, publications, and an issue of Eugenics News, 1930
- Subject files related to Chinese Americans and Chinatown, 1930s-1970s. (Box 372)
  Includes some correspondence
  - San Francisco Chinatown (Box 372)
  - New York Chinatown (Box 372)
  - Washington DC, Chinese American communities (Box 372)
  - Chinese playground, San Francisco, notes and draft writings (Box 372)
  - Political clippings, in English and in Chinese (Box 372)
  - Professions (Box 372)
  - San Francisco Chinatown nightclubs and burlesque shows (Box 372)
  - The Asian Student, issues, 1950s (Box 372)
  - Chinese News issues (San Francisco: publishers Jake W. Lee and Charles Leong), 1950s (Box 372)
  - Prejudice and discrimination in the U.S. Clippings, 1944-1960s (Box 372)
  - Higher education clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 372)
  - Segregation of people of Chinese descent ephemera, including by the YMCA and YWCA (Box 372)
- Department of State Education Officer files and USIS files, 1960s-1970s (Box 373)
  - 1972 study trip files, 1972, undated. (Box 373)
    Destinations included Hong Kong, Tokyo, and Taipei
  - East-West Center subject file, 1960s-1970s. (Box 373)
  - Department of State Education Officer files and USIS files, 1960s-1970s (Box 373)
  - The Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange between East and West, University of Hawaii, Honolulu documents (Box 373)
  - Correspondence, including letter in which Lowe outlines the origins of the East West Center from the 1930s onward, 1973 February 9 (Box 373)
  - Lowe's curriculum vitae, 1973 February 9 (Box 373)
- FBI and CIA clippings file, 1950s-1970s. (Box 373)
  Includes note regarding an FBI interview, 1953 May 17, and letters from James N. Wong to Low, 1950
- Harvard Business School notes and documents related to foreign trade, 1929-1932 (Box 373)
- Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 373)
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1960s-1970s. (Box 374)
  Mainly related to UNESCO and AID, including printed material, administrative documents, holographic notes, and correspondence regarding recruitment, 1963-1972
- National Security Industrial Association, Project Aristotle (Annual Review and Information Symposium on the Technology of Training, Learning and Education) materials, 1968, undated (Box 374)
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1960s-1970s. (Box 375)
  Consists mainly of UNESCO documents and reports related to personnel and candidates, 1960s-1970s.
  - Nairobi Conference documents, 1968, undated (Box 375)
  - "U.S. Delegation Guidance Book, Conference on Education and Scientific and Technical Training in Relation to Development in Africa, Nairobi, July 16-27, 1968," U.S. Department of State, undated (Box 375)
  - East West Center survey files, correspondence and itineraries, 1969-1971 (Box 375)
  - Peace Corps clippings and printed documents, 1960s-1970s (Box 375)
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1960s-1970s. (Box 376)
  - Personnel evaluations, 1960s-1970s (Box 376)
  - CU/MPP manual of standard operating procedures, 1969 (Box 376)
  - UNDP and UNICEF documents, 1960s-1970s (Box 376)
- Peace Corps clippings and printed documents, 1960s-1970s. (Box 376)
- Vietnam subject files, 1966-1975. (Box 377)
- United Nations clippings, 1960s-1973 (Box 377)
- United Nations subject files, 1960s-1970s (Box 378)
- International politics subject files, 1928-1960s (Box 378)
- Disarmament subject files, 1928-1960s (Box 378)
- Stanford University coursework notes, 1928-1930 (Box 378)
- Clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 378)
- Clippings, 1930s-1990s (Box 379)
- Clippings related to Taiwan, Japan, and Hong Kong, 1988 (Box 380)
- Writing files, 1929s-1970s. (Box 381)
  Includes draft writings, 1930s, undated, and correspondence with potential book publishers. Also includes clippings
  - Semi-autobiographical, historical, and, sociological novel proposal letter including detailed biographical information, 1935 May 8 (Box 381)
  - "Chinatown in Transition," typescript, 1937-1938 (Box 381)
  - Letters to the editor, 1940 (Box 381)
  - "Political writings" for the San Francisco Chronicle, 1930s (Box 381)
  - "Permanent Projects" list, holographic, undated, probably 1970s (Box 381)
- Writings by others, including related to the Burma-China Highway, 1939 (Box 381)
- Chinatowns and Chinese Americans research files, 1920s-1970s. (Box 382-385.)
  Includes draft writings, notes, correspondence, ephemera, and newspaper clippings, in English and in Chinese
  - Chinese Americans (Box 382-385.)
  - Chinatowns, especially of New York, San Francisco, and Oakland (Box 382-385.)
  - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939 (Box 382-385.)
  - Organizations for youth, including under segregation (Box 382-385.)
  - YMCA (Box 382-385.)
  - Chinese playground (San Francisco) (Box 382-385.)
  - Family associations (Box 382-385.)
  - District associations (Box 382-385.)
  - Tongs (Box 382-385.)
  - Peace Society (San Francisco) (Box 382-385.)
  - Native Sons of the Golden State, later known as Chinese American Citizens Alliance (CACA) (Box 382-385.)
- China-Burma-India Veterans Association of San Francisco (Box 382-385.)
- Clippings flies related to writing (Box 382)
- Reverend Ng Poon Chew's address to Masons Lakeside Lodge No. 551, outlining the history of Chinese and Chinese Americans' association with Masons and encouraging the opening of Masonic membership to Chinese Americans (Box 384)
- State Department subject files, 1960s-1970s (Box 384)
  consisting of clippings and administrative documents
- Peace Corps clippings, 1961-1963 (Box 385)
- UNESCO work documents, 1960s-1970s. (Box 386)
  Includes some correspondence and draft writings
- Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box 386)
- Department of State Education Officer files, 1960s-1970s. (Box 387)
  Consists mainly of printed materials related to UNESCO
- "Proceedings of the Fourth Annual Meeting of the Social Science Research Conference of the Pacific Coast," San Francisco, 1934 June 13-15 (Box 387)